# **JOHN MAGUIRE**

### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

■ john@johnmaguiredeveloper.com • 631-877-0533 • Brooklyn, NY in johnmaguire1 • jm96441n

# **SUMMARY**

It was during college when I discovered my passion for mathematics, and analytic problem solving in general, but I felt advancing further in the field would not provide me with a sufficient creative output. From there it was a long, diverse road that brought me to my current position. Through all of these experiences I learned many different things about myself, and found a love for coding. The ability to solve a problem in a multitude of different ways, with each solution having different merits really speaks to me, and I am really looking forward to turning this newfound passion into a lifelong career.

### **EDUCATION**

### Pace University

B.S. Mathematics 2010

#### DevBootcamp

19 Week Full Stack Development Bootcamp 2016

# **PROJECTS**

#### MyToiletPal

A web app that allows the user to see all public toilets around them, review public toilets, as well as add toilets that are not currently in our database. Built using Ruby on Rails the Web App. A mobile app is in the process of being made.

#### ICYMI (In Case You Missed It)

An IOS app, with a webapp component, that shows the user a searchable list of every business they pass throughout the day in order to help them find places they may have missed during their day. Built with Rails on the backend, React Native for the mobile app and React for the webapp frontend.

#### Yoda Know

A star wars themed Stack Overflow clone. Built with Sinatra for the backend and using JQuery on the frontend.

# **SKILLS**

LANGUAGES: Javascript, Ruby, HTML, CSS, SQL

MATHEMATICS: Calculus (through intro to Differential Equations), Linear Algebra, Algebraic Structures,

Complex Analysis, Real Analysis, Discrete Mathematics with Combinatorics

FRAMEWORKS: Ruby on Rails, React, React Native, Sinatra, JQuery

TOOLS: Git, Heroku, Adobe Illustrator

# **ACTIVITIES**

#### TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon 2016

Competed in the TechCrunch Disrupt Hackathon. With a team of 5, we built a rails app that connects students to after school activities, and allows them to suggest new activities that they are interested in. If a teacher approves and an idea get's enough votes from other students, the activity opens up to parents to crowdfund the new activity to make it a reality.

## **EMPLOYMENT**

### Superfine

Server

Server at a farm to table restaurant. Menu changed everyday, which required me to adapt and be able to describe new dishes everyday to patrons.

CL Design

Brooklyn, NY Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Sep 2009 to Feb 2016

Brooklyn, NY

Worked in the fabrication of custom chandeliers. Finished and stained different types of metals.

Office Assistant

Metal Finisher

Aug 2015 to Feb 2016

Assisted with various office tasks (editing product catalogs, uploading new photo's of chandeliers to the website, customer outreach).

Math Tutor

New York, NY Sep 2007 to May 2015

Self-Employed

Self-employed math tutor. Worked with children from first grade up through eleventh grade.